<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Nematodeinfo</string>

    <string name="footer"> Dr. PANKAJ , HARENDER KUMAR AND ANJANI KUMAR , 2017</string>


    <string-array name="crops">
        <item>Rice</item>
        <item>Wheat</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="Rice_Nematodes">
        <item>M.Graminicola</item>
        <item>Hirscmanniella</item>
        <item>Ditylenchus</item>
        <item>Aphelenchoides besseyi</item>
    </string-array>

    <integer-array name="Rice_Nematodes_images">
        <item>@drawable/common_google_signin_btn_text_light_disabled</item>
        <item>@drawable/rice</item>
        <item>@drawable/rice</item>
        <item>@drawable/rice</item>
    </integer-array>

    <string-array name="Wheat_Nematodes">
        <item>Heterodera</item>
    </string-array>

    <integer-array name="Wheat_Nematodes_images">
        <item>@drawable/wheat</item>
    </integer-array>



















    <string name="rice_1_intro">
  In northern India, there is a shift in cultivation of rice in the wheat growing belt of Punjab, Haryana and Uttar Pradesh. Most of the farmers of non-traditional areas in Haryana-khadar belt grow rice in sandy soil with low water holding capacity. Thus, rice is grown under shallow water conditions, which is more conducive for the multiplication of M. graminicola.
    </string>
    
    
    
    <string name="rice_1_spread">
  Rice root-knot nematode is widely distributed in South-East Asia and USA, both in upland and deepwater rice. Severe damage occurs in upland and sometimes in transplanted rice in north-eastern states, West Bengal, Odisha, Bihar, Eastern Uttar Pradesh, Chhattisgarh, parts of Madhya Pradesh and Karnataka. Pockets of heavy infestation of rice nurseries and transplanted crop have been noticed in north-Indian plains including Jammu, Punjab, Himachal Pradesh, Haryana, Delhi and Uttar Pradesh. The nematode has also been reported in Andaman and Nicobar Islands.
This nematode infecting wheat and rice are carried passively to newer places through  transportation of infected rice seedlings, flowing irrigation and runoff water, movement of soil containing eggs and bits of dried infected roots through cattle and human feet, farm machinery, weed, wind, etc. and suckers of banana.

    </string>
    
    
    <string name="rice_1_symptoms">
     In general, infested rice plants show less vigour, yellowing and curling of leaves.  The chlorophyll content of leaves is reduced. The most characteristic symptom is formation of root galls, which are terminal, spiral or horse-shoe shaped.  The crop has poor stand, less tillering and fewer effective tillers. The spikes become smaller and fewer with poorly filled grains, thus reducing the yield.
In deep water rice, the nematode infested seedlings remain stunted, unable to grow above flood water and perish due to continuous submergence.

    </string>
    <string name="rice_1_management">

        1.  Nursery-bed treatment\n\n
•	Selection of an area for nursery, free from root-knot nematode.\n
•	Soil solarization of the area for nursery-beds, for 3-6 weeks in late April-May (summer).\n
•	Application of carbofuran or phorate @ 3.3 g per sq m.\n\n
2.  Treatment of main field\n\n
•	Puddling of the main field before transplanting.\n
•	Summer ploughing of the main field, twice at 2 weeks interval.\n
•	Avoiding direct sowing of rice in the main field.\n
•	Crop rotation with non-host crops.\n
•	Late sowing of wheat during late November to mid-December with a suitable variety.\n
•	Green manuring with Sesbania spp. or Crotolaria spp., if time permits.\n



    </string>


    <!-- Rice 2-->
     <string name="rice_2_intro">
   The genus Hirschmanniella includes at present about 35 species. More than half of them have been recorded on rice and can be found in tropical and subtropical regions of the world including the Southern USA, China and Japan. The non-rice species are found in the same region and in the northern temperate zone (less than 10 species). All members are obligate migratory endoparasites of roots and are adapted to a broad range of moist habitats with a preference for graminaceous roots (Loof, 1991). In addition some dicotyledonous plants such as cotton are hosts, including some weeds. Hirschmanniella has also been detected on roots and leaves of aquatic plants and in soil associated with bonsais. On rice, it is common to detect several species of Hirschmanniella. </string>



    <string name="rice_2_spread">
     Hirschmanniella spp. are observed throughout rice- and non-rice-growing regions of the world, including the United States, but is most commonly found in tropical and subtropical regions of Asia. This nematode has been identified in the Asian countries viz., Myanmar, India, Pakistan, Bangladesh, Sri Lanka, Nepal, Thailand, Vietnam, Indonesia, the Philippines, China, Korea, and Japan.

    </string>


    <string name="rice_2_symptoms">
      The general symptoms of Hirschmanniella spp. are not specific. On rice retardation of growth, decrease in culm height, reduction in weight of dry matter, delayed tillering; fewer shoots and discolouration of the older leaves have been reported.

    </string>

    <string name="rice_2_management">
\n•	Since both eggs and juveniles can overwinter in dead roots. In response to rice paddy desiccation, these nematodes can survive by entering an anhydrobiotic state until the rains begin, which allows the nematode populations to remain dormant.  Therefore, control measures have proven with little success. Also, certain control measures such as the use of nematicides are not economically feasible since rice does not have a high enough cash value in developing countries\n
\n•	Weed control and natural resistances of rice are possible control measures that may prove more effective.\n
\n•	Proper cultural practices can provide satisfactory plant stand though heavily infected, which allows for a level of tolerance of rice to RRN.

    </string>











     <string name="rice_3_intro">
   Ditylenchus angustus is synonymous with Tylenchus angustus Butler, 1913 and Anguillulina angusta (Butler) Goodey. It is also referred to as the ufra nematode deriving its name from the disease it causes in rice (ufra).  Ufra disease is known locally in Bangladesh as “dak pora” (because the field damage caused by the nematode resembles that caused by a lightning strike); in Myanmar this nematode is known as “akhet-pet” and in Vietnam as “tiem dot san”.
\n\n
Other host are:\n
\nEchinochloa colona (junglerice)\n
Leersia hexandra (southern cut grass)\n
Oryza (rice (generic level))\n
Sacciolepsis interrupta\n
</string>



    <string name="rice_3_spread">
    Ditylenchus angustus is adapted to flooded soils and to the high temperatures that occur in many of the irrigated, rain-fed lowland, upland, deepwater and tidal wetland rice-growing regions around the world (Bridge et al., 2005). The nematode has been reported in Bangladesh, India, Indonesia, Malaysia, Myanmar, the Philippines, Thailand and Vietnam. D. angustus has a limited geographical distribution and it is solely a pest of rice, although it does occur on different types of flooded rice from deepwater to lowland irrigated. It has been recorded and confirmed on rice from India, Bangladesh, Thailand, Myanmar and Vietnam.
\n
The reproduction in D. angustus is amphimictic with males as numerous as females within a population. The life cycle is of 10 to 20 days at 30 °C, and at least three generations may occur within one growing season, lays 50 and 120 eggs in a lifetime.

    </string>


    <string name="rice_3_symptoms">

\n•	During vegetative growth from seedling to flag leaf, the principal symptom of infection is leaf chlorosis. In light infections, the chlorosis will be discrete white spots, less than 1 mm in diameter. As nematode numbers increase, these spots become more numerous, intensify and coalesce towards the base of the penultimate leaf and lower part of the emerging leaf.\n
\n•	D. angustus does feed on the inner surface of the leaf sheaths, but these rarely show obvious symptoms. In time the chlorotic areas will show some localized browning.\n
\n•	Depending on the severity of infection, chlorotic leaf areas, tillers or whole plants will wither and die, attaining a light-brown appearance. In severe infections, the entire crop takes on this appearance.
\n•	If infected tillers survive to flowering then the panicles remain partially or completely enclosed within the leaf sheath. Partially emerged panicles bear few, if any, true seed and the empty spikelets are distorted and discoloured.



    </string>
    <string name="rice_3_management">
  \n      •	Burning of crop residues to eliminate all infested stem terminals extending the overwintering period by delayed planting\n
\n•	D. angustus survives for a limited period: lengthening the overwintering period can reduce primary infection This can be achieved with deepwater rice by using short-duration cultivars\n
\n•	The use of resistant cultivars, when they become available, should prove to be the most effective measure\n
\n•	Growing a non-host crop, such as jute, in rotation with deepwater rice can reduce the incidence of ufra in fields.\n
\n•	Removal of ratoon rice plants, wild rice and other host weeds will help prevent the carryover between seasons, and banks between plots may also be beneficial.\n
\n•	Where it is possible, submerging young seedlings for a week would reduce infection in lowland rice. Maintaining water levels well below the top of the leaf-sheath collar throughout the crop in lowland rice reduce nematode dispersal and secondary and tertiary infection.\n
\n•	A large number of deepwater and lowland rice cultivars have been tested against D. angustus. The cultivars Padmapani and Digha are not attacked by D. angustus in areas of India and Bangladesh.

    </string>















         <string name="rice_4_intro" formatted="false">
   Aphelenchoides besseyi is seed borne, affects rice crop grown in humid areas. It is widely distributed and now occurs in most rice growing areas.
</string>



    <string name="rice_4_spread" formatted="false">
 A. besseyi is not found beyond latitude 43° N on rice or beyond 40° N on strawberries.  Locally established in Bulgaria, Hungary (Javor, 1970), Italy, Russia (European), Slovakia; reported from but not established in Israel and France.\n
\n<b>Asia</b>: Afghanistan, Azerbaijan, Bangladesh, Cambodia, China (widespread), India (widespread), Indonesia, Iran, Israel (reported but not established), Japan (unconfirmed), Korea Republic, Lao, Malaysia, Myanmar, Nepal, Pakistan, Philippines, Sri Lanka, Taiwan, Tajikistan, Thailand, Uzbekistan, Viet Nam.\n
\nAfrica: Benin, Burkina Faso, Burundi, Cameroon, Central African Republic, Chad, Comoros, Côte d\'Ivoire, Egypt, Gabon, Gambia, Ghana, Kenya, Madagascar, Malawi, Mali, Nigeria, Senegal, Sierra Leone, South Africa, Tanzania, Togo, Uganda, Zaire, Zambia, Zimbabwe.\n
\nNorth America: Mexico, USA (Arizona, California, Florida, Hawaii, Louisiana, Texas).\n
\nCentral America and Caribbean: Cuba, Dominica, Dominican Republic, El Salvador, Guadeloupe, Panama.\n
\nSouth America: Argentina, Brazil (Bahia, Minas Gerais, Parana, Rondonia, Santa Catarina, São Paulo), Ecuador.\n
\nOceania: Australia (Queensland, Northern Territory), Fiji.\n
\nThe optimum temperature for development is 21-25°C, the life cycle taking 10 days at 21°C and 8 days at 23°C, and there are several generations in a season.
   </string>


    <string name="rice_4_symptoms" formatted="false">

Affected plants show white-tip or whip-like malformation of the top third of the leaf blade. Nematodes invade the florets through the tunnel below the apiculus where lemma and palea remain open. In flowering tillers, chaffiness and abnormal elongation of glumes in some spikelets, rachii and rachillae were observed (Todd and Atkins, 1958; Rao, 1970). Cell damage to the outer wall of the ovary causes partial filling of kernels and damage to the lodicules prevents closure of flower after anthesis, exposing the embryo to environmental stresses like desiccation, infection by Alternaria (Trichoconis) padwikii (Ganguly) Ellis and spikelet sterility (Rao and Rao, 1979). During rice development, Tsay et al. (1998) found A. besseyi feeding endoparasitically in the coleoptile for 7-10 days and ectoparasitically within the innermost leaf sheath during other plant growth stages. At late tillering, nematode numbers increased rapidly, and reached a peak during the plant reproductive stage. Infected plants showed reduced vigour, height and weight of spikelets and number of grains.
\n
On strawberries\n
There is leaf crinkling and distortion, and dwarfing of the plant with an associated reduction in flowering.\n
On other hosts\n
A. besseyi may be endoparasitic, as in Ficus elastica and Polianthes tuberosa, in which it causes leaf drop and leaf lesions, respectively. In the grass Sporobolus poirettii, the nematode stimulates growth, resulting in increased inflorescences.
For additional information, see Yoshii &amp; Yamamoto (1950), Todd &amp; Atkins (1958), Feakin (1971), Franklin &amp; Siddiqi (1972), Luc et al. (1990).
\n
Morphology\n
besseyi has a slender body 0.44-0.84 mm long and 14-22 μm wide. In females, the excretory pore is usually near the anterior edge of the nerve ring; the spermatheca is elongate-oval and packed with sperm; the ovary is relatively short, the post-vulval uterine sac narrow, and the terminus bears a mucro of diverse shape with three to four pointed processes. In males, the proximal end of the spicule lacks a dorsal process.


    </string>
    <string name="rice_4_management" formatted="false">
       <b> Varietal resistance:</b>\n

          The most effective control method was the use of pathogen-free seed or resistant varieties (Silva and da Silva, 1992). Oliveira and Oliveira (1989) reported that the genotypes Bluebelle, BR-IRGA 409 and IRGA 172 F4 SS39 in Brazil did not show symptoms of white tip when inoculated with A. besseyi. In USSR, utilizing the progenitors of almost all the resistant varieties bred there in the last 40 years are Fortuna, Nira, Rexoro and Bluebonnet, and in particular Rexoro (from which Bluebonnet was bred), a notable derivative Bonnet 73, with multiple resistance to A. besseyi and various diseases was developed (Zelenskii and Popova, 1991).

\n\n <b>Physical:</b>\n

          Aleksandrova and Beloglazov (1989) reported that storage of A. besseyi infected seed in regulated gas medium (97.5% nitrogen and 2.5% oxygen) for 10 days at 25øC gave the best control results. Seed treatments with either ethoprophos 20EC at 0.5%/100 liters, or hot water at 53-54oC for 15 reduced the infestation of nematode to almost nematode-free level (Tacconi et al., 1999). In addition to hot water treatment, a combination of benomyl seed treatment (at 0.3% by seed weight) and spraying (at 2.5 g/dm3) 1 or 15 days after transplanting protected rice plants from infestation by A. besseyi and  produced nematode free seeds (Gergon and Prot, 1993a).

\n\n<b>Cultural:</b>\n

           In irrigated rice, damage due to the nematode was limited when rice was sown directly into water rather than flooded after sowing (Silva and da Silva, 1992).

\n\n<b>Regulatory:</b>\n

Legislation prohibiting the sale of infested seed was urged (Silva and da Silva, 1992). In a bid to develop a quarantine treatment schedule, Prasad and Varaprasad (1992) tried sixteen treatment combinations in 10 rice entries heavily infested with white-tip nematode for its elimination. The treatment schedule of soaking of the seed in 0.2% solution of mancozeb and monocrotophos followed by vacuum fumigation (methyl bromide ca 32 g/m3) for 2 h at 30øC could eliminate the nematode in all the test entries. Even when the vacuum fumigation was substituted with atmospheric fumigation (aluminium phosphide @ 9.3 g/m3), the treatment schedule was equally effective. Soaking in water followed by hot water treatment (52øC for 30 min.) and vacuum fumigation, though effective in elimination of white-tip nematode, resulted in complete loss of seed viability.

\n\n<b>Chemical:</b>\n

.      Seed treatment with carbofuran, thiobendazole, benomyl or fenitrothion reduced nematodes to very low levels, but they were not entirely eliminated (Silva and da Silva,1992). Control was achieved to over 90% by using Xianjunling to soak rice seeds for 48 h (Qiu et al., 1991). Pre-soaking seed with oxamyl or hot water treatment reduced the infestation rate and increased yields (Tsay et al., 1998). In USSR, pre-sowing treatment of rice with the organic mercury compound Granozan and hydrogen peroxide reduced Aphelenchoides infestation of rice panicles, improved the density of the rice stands by 10 to 11% and increased the yields by 13% and 23 to 36%. Hydrogen peroxide quickly decomposed unlike Granozan which accumulates in the soil and in the grain and is toxic to mammals (Anikeev and Shabel\'-nikov, 1980). Kumar and Sivakumar (1998) observed  monocrotophos sprayed at 1000 ml/ha at the boot leaf stage, reduced the white tip incidence and grain chaffiness, and increased the yield of rice in field experiments.


    </string>





















    <string name="wheat_1_intro" formatted="false">
        Cereal cyst nematode (CCN) H. avenae is the most important nematode of wheat, barley, oat, rye, maize and other graminaceous plants. H. avenae was first reported on wheat in Germany in 1874 (Kuhn, 1874).
    </string>



    <string name="wheat_1_spread" formatted="false">
    It is distributed widely throughout many wheat growing areas of the world, including Europe, India, Canada, the USA, China, Pakistan, Iran, Saudi Arabia, Israel, Morocco, Tunisia, Pakistan, Libya, Estonia and Australia, assuming the importance of a major limiting factor. In India, Vasudeva first detected H. avenae on the roots of wheat in 1958 in the village of Nim ka Thana in the Sikar District of Rajasthan. Since then, it has been recognized as an endemic problem in the agro-climatic zones of northern to central India, comprising the states of Punjab, Haryana, Uttar Pradesh, Himachal Pradesh, Jammu and Kashmir, Delhi and Madhya Pradesh.
	\nAs the cyst stage is able to withstand the harsh environmental conditions and is disseminated through the movement of soil with machinery, animals, water, dust storm, and any means by which soil is disseminated.

    </string>


    <string name="wheat_1_symptoms" formatted="false">
    As the life cycle of CCNs progresses, several white females in the form of cysts are usually visible at each knot.\n
1. Distinct patches of yellowed and stunted plants in the field.\n
2. Great reduction in the Tillering\n
3. Culms become thinner and weaker\n
4. Affected plants flower prematurely and ear heads bear fewer grains\n
5. Roots become bushy with slight swelling marking at the sites of nematode infection.\n
6. Appearance of white glistening females on roots during January/February is the only and exact diagnostic symptom of presence of cereal cyst nematode on crop.\n


    </string>

    <string name="wheat_1_management" formatted="false">
\n        1.	Deep summer ploughings 2 to 3 times at an interval of 10 to 15 days between  May and June( reducing nematode population due to desiccation)
\n2.	Fallowing checks population build-up by starvation of emerged juveniles
\n3.	Change in time of planting
\n4.	Early sowing of wheat in first fortnight of November ( By the time peak hatching / infection occurs, the crop is already 1-2 months old and can sustain damage due to nematodes)
\n5.	Trap crop: Oats used as trap crop for reducing cereal cyst nematode
\n6.	Crop Rotation: Crop rotation with non-host crops like Mustard, Chickpea, coriander, cumin, fenugreek, or carrots for 1-2 years. Population gets reduced from 47 to 55% at the end of one year.
\n7.	Organic amendment: Mustard cake amendment can affect hatching of cysts mustard contain contains allyl isothiocyanate which is toxic to nematode.
\n8.	The use of chemicals becomes economic when other methods of control are too costly, difficult to apply, or when a method such as rotation is inadequate. Today however, no chemical is considered adequate because of costs, environmental hazards, and high health risks for farmers.



    </string>


    <string name="title_activity_cropnema">Cropnema</string>
    <string name="title_activity_tab5">Tab5</string>
    <string name="title_activity_settings">Settings</string>

    <!-- Strings related to Settings -->

    <!-- Example General settings -->
    <string name="pref_header_general">General</string>

    <string name="pref_title_social_recommendations">Enable social recommendations</string>
    <string name="pref_description_social_recommendations">Recommendations for people to contact
        based on your message history
    </string>

    <string name="pref_title_display_name">Display name</string>
    <string name="pref_default_display_name">John Smith</string>

    <string name="pref_title_add_friends_to_messages">Add friends to messages</string>
    <string-array name="pref_example_list_titles">
        <item>Always</item>
        <item>When possible</item>
        <item>Never</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="pref_example_list_values">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>0</item>
        <item>-1</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- Example settings for Data & Sync -->
    <string name="pref_header_data_sync">Data &amp; sync</string>

    <string name="pref_title_sync_frequency">Sync frequency</string>
    <string-array name="pref_sync_frequency_titles">
        <item>15 minutes</item>
        <item>30 minutes</item>
        <item>1 hour</item>
        <item>3 hours</item>
        <item>6 hours</item>
        <item>Never</item>
    </string-array>
    <string-array name="pref_sync_frequency_values">
        <item>15</item>
        <item>30</item>
        <item>60</item>
        <item>180</item>
        <item>360</item>
        <item>-1</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="list_preference_entries">
        <item>Entry 1</item>
        <item>Entry 2</item>
        <item>Entry 3</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="list_preference_entry_values">
        <item>1</item>
        <item>2</item>
        <item>3</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="multi_select_list_preference_default_value" />

    <string name="pref_title_system_sync_settings">System sync settings</string>

    <!-- Example settings for Notifications -->
    <string name="pref_header_notifications">Notifications</string>

    <string name="pref_title_new_message_notifications">New message notifications</string>

    <string name="pref_title_ringtone">Ringtone</string>
    <string name="pref_ringtone_silent">Silent</string>

    <string name="pref_title_vibrate">Vibrate</string>


</resources>
